双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译     卖力杀猪
翻译    FuriousFurion
翻译    盗墓奸尸
君临 King's Landing
翻译    Bran的夏天
红堡
Red Keep
校对    临冬城的狮子
校对    pksunking
龙石岛 Dragonstone
复校    旧镇老翁
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
复校   凯冯・兰尼斯特 波隆・史铎克渥斯
临冬城 Winterfell
精校   龙的命根子
监制    临冬城的狮子 北落师门
后期   poplar
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
阿斯塔波Astapor
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治・R・R・马丁
权力的游戏
第三季 第二集
衣柜字幕组
史诗图书 正统奇幻的圣殿
第二集  "Dark Wings, Dark Words "
黑色翅膀 黑色消息
不要想太多 布兰
Don't think too much, Bran.
布兰・史塔克
把手臂放松
Relax your bow arm.
你们当中有谁在10岁时就是神射手的？
And which one of you was a marksman at 10?
父亲？
Father?
你不能杀死它
You can't kill it, you know.
为什么？
Why not?
因为那只乌鸦就是你
Because the raven is you.
毛毛狗
“毛毛”  瑞肯・史塔克的冰原狼
夏天
布兰・史塔克的冰原狼
瑞肯・史塔克
阿多
临冬城的马僮
Hodor.
没事的 阿多
It's all right, Hodor.
阿多
Hodor.
欧莎
女野人
你是不是又进入狼的体内了 小王子？
Were you inside the wolf again, little lord?
不 是三眼乌鸦
No, it was the three-eyed raven.
他回来了
He's back.
我尝试杀死它 但我做不到
I tried to kill it, but I couldn't.
- 梦里有个男孩 - 我不想听这些
- There was a boy. - I don't want to hear about it.
- 但你开口问了 - 我们的烦恼够多了
- But you asked. - We've got plenty of worries.
不需要把黑暗魔法也加进来
We don't need to pour black magic on top of them.
我没要做黑魔法的梦
I didn't ask for black magic dreams.
我知道你不没有 小主人
I know you didn't, little lord.
我们得出发了
We need to move.
不知道谁可能在追着我们
We don't know who might be after us.
没有人知道我们还活着
No one even knows we're alive.
谁告诉你的？
And who told you that?
三眼乌鸦告诉你的？
The three-eyed raven tell you?
- 不是 - 那他还挺好
- No. - Some good he is, then.
我不知道别人知道什么不知道什么
I don't know what other people know and what they don't.
我只知道到长城还很远的路要走
I only know the Wall is a long way off.
泰丽莎・梅吉尔
小护士 罗柏的王后
我妈妈经常跟我讲
My mother always told me
你们维斯特洛人是一帮无情的家伙
you Westerosi were a grim lot.
是冷血的 长胡子的 臭哄哄的
Grim, bearded,
罗柏・史塔克
北境之王
蛮子
stinking barbarians
你们会渡过狭海
that would row across the Narrow Sea
趁我们睡觉时把我们偷偷绑走
and steal us from our beds.
你可曾想过你会嫁给一个这样的人？
Did you ever think you'd marry one?
我从没想过我会嫁给任何一个人
I never thought I'd marry anyone at all.
从来没有？
Never?
直到我遇见了
Not until I met the king of the grim,
冷血的 长胡子的 臭哄哄的蛮子王
bearded, stinking barbarians.
抱歉 陛下
Pardon me, Your Grace.
- 吾后 - 波顿大人
- My queen. - Lord Bolton.
卢斯・波顿
恐怖堡伯爵
让我来猜猜哪个是好消息
Let me guess which one is the good news.
信件来自奔流城
Word from Riverrun
和临冬城
and Winterfell.
我好多年没见过他了
I hadn't seen him in years.
都不知道到底有多少年
I don't even know how many.
我们一同前去参加葬礼
We'll travel to the funeral together.
凯特琳・徒利
艾德・史塔克的遗孀
在我们回来之前
Lord Bolton will garrison here
波顿大人会据守在此地
until we return.
在安葬我父亲的时候 我要带着手铐吗？
Will I be wearing manacles when I lay my father to rest?
还有别的消息？
Something else?
当波顿家的私生子到达临冬城的时候
By the time Bolton's bastard got to Winterfell,
铁民已经离去
the ironborn were gone.
他们残杀了所有人 将城堡付之一炬
They massacred everyone and put the castle to the torch.
布兰和瑞肯无处可寻
And Bran and Rickon have not been found.
没准他们逃脱了
They may have escaped.
没准席恩把他们带回铁群岛充当人质
Or Theon may have taken them back to the Iron Islands as hostages.
你有收到什么要挟吗？
Have you received any demands?
没有
No.
你有收到过席恩的丝毫消息吗？
Have you heard anything from Theon at all?
席恩・葛雷乔伊
铁群岛继承人
我在哪儿？
Where am I?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你想干什么？
What do you want?
我想干这个
I want to do this.
你知道这样徒步穿越田野森林
Do you know how long it's going to take us
詹姆・兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
要多久才能走到君临吗？
to get to King's Landing walking through fields and forests?
我知道
Yes.
布蕾妮・塔斯
“美人” 凯特琳的护卫
那我们怎么打发时间呢？
So how shall we pass the time?
一步一个脚印地走
By putting one foot in front of the other.
那旅程会很无聊的
It's going to be a very dull walk.
我的任务是把你带到君临城
I'm here to take you to King's Landing
以换回史塔克夫人的女儿们
and bring back Lady Stark's daughters in exchange.
无聊就无聊呗
Dull is fine.
你知道 无论你如何忠诚
You know, it doesn't matter how loyal a servant you are,
也没人愿意和你这种傻大个为伍
no one enjoys the company of a humorless mute.
相信我
Trust me on this.
打我出生起 就有人开始侍奉我
People have been serving me since I was born.
你觉得史塔克夫人会想要一个淡黄色头发的傻大个
You think Lady Stark is going to want a giant towheaded plank
伴随她终生？
following her around for the rest of her life?
过不了一个星期她就想命令你自裁了
A week's journey with you and she'll order you to fall on your sword.
如果史塔克夫人对我有任何不满
If Lady Stark is unhappy with any aspect of my service,
我相信她会让我知道的
I'm sure she'll let me know.
她是一个诚实的女人
She's an honest woman.
这是她唯一的优点了
All the good it's done her.
你是怎么开始侍奉史塔克夫人的？
How did you come into Lady Stark's service?
我们可以好好聊聊
There's something we can talk about.
不关你的事 弑君者
Not your concern, Kingslayer.
应该是最近的事
It had to be recently.
她在临冬城的时候你没跟着她
You weren't with her at Winterfell.
你怎么知道？
How would you know?
因为我去过临冬城
Because I visited Winterfell.
我难道看到过你那石头脑瓜
I would have noticed your dour head
顶到拱门？
smacking into the archways.
快走
Move.
- 你是否曾效忠史坦尼斯？ - 天哪 没有
- Were you pledged to Stannis? - Gods, no.
啊 蓝礼
Ah, Renly.
真的吗？
Really?
他不适合管理比一桌十二道菜的酒席
He wasn't fit to rule over anything
更重要的东西
more important than a 12-course meal.
- 闭上你的嘴 - 为啥？
- Shut your mouth. - Why?
别忘了他从小就和我一起生活在宫廷里
I lived with him at court since he was a boy, don't forget.
那小小郁金香身着绣花丝衣 在长廊中连跑带跳的场面
Could hardly escape the little tulip.
实在是无法忘怀
Skipping down the corridors in his embroidered silks.
我对他的了解比你多得多
I knew him far better than you.
我对他的了解无人能及
I knew him as well as anyone.
作为他的御林铁卫
As a member of his Kingsguard,
他对我无所不谈
he trusted me with everything.
他会是一个好国王
He would have been a wonderful king.
听起来你很爱慕他
Sounds like you quite fancied him.
我不爱慕他
I did not fancy him.
哦 天哪 你爱他
Oh, gods, you did.
你有跟他说过吗？
Did you ever tell him?
不 当然没有
No, of course not.
恐怕你不是蓝礼喜欢的类型
You weren't Renly's type, I'm afraid.
他更喜欢洛拉斯・提利尔这样的卷发小女孩
He preferred curly-haired little girls like Loras Tyrell.
你阳刚之气太重了
You're far too much man for him.
我对这些下流的流言没兴趣
I'm not interested in foul rumors.
除非是关于我的
Unless they're about me.
这些关于蓝礼的话都是真的
It's all true about Renly.
他的性取向在宫中简直无人不晓
His proclivities were the worst kept secret at court.
真可惜王座不是用阳具做的
It's a shame the throne isn't made out of cocks.
- 估计人们是没法将他从上面拉下来的 - 闭上你的嘴
- They'd have never got him off it. - Shut your mouth!
我没指责他
I don't blame him.
我也没指责你
And I don't blame you, either.
爱上谁不是我们自己能做主的
We don't get to choose who we love.
- 你们是要去哪里？ - 南方
- Where are you headed, then? - South.
- 你呢？ - 奔流城
- You? - Riverrun.
躲着国王大道是吧？
Staying off the kingsroad, are you?
不管你到哪里他们都能找到你
They get you no matter where you go.
- 你们躲不掉 - 是啊 真的躲不掉
- You can't win. - No, you really can't.
不过看起来你倒挺安全
Looks like you're safe enough, though.
无意冒犯 女士 不过……
Meaning no offense, my lady, but...
我不想和你们纠缠
I wouldn't tangle with you.
- 七神保佑你们 - 也保佑你
- Seven blessings to you. - And you.
他知道我是谁
He knows who I am.
- 他不知道 - 也许你是对的
- He doesn't. - Maybe you're right.
但如果你错了呢 如果他告密咋办？
But what if you're not? What if he tells someone?
我们不能杀掉他
We're not doing it.
他是无辜的
He's an innocent man.
比史塔克夫人的女儿们还无辜？
More innocent than Lady Stark's daughters?
乔佛里・拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
这里紧一些
Make it tighter here.
好多了
That's better.
让你看起来更强壮
It makes you look very strong.
不要带花的
No flowers.
我说了不要带花的
I said no flowers.
这些不好 拿其他的来
All these are wrong. Bring others.
遵命 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
该死的花
Bloody flowers.
戴在国王身上
On the king.
看起来跟提利尔的玫瑰一样
Looks like a Tyrell rose.
送给玛格利装饰她的礼服好了
Give it to Margaery for her wedding gown.
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
应该够用了
Should be more than enough fabric.
告诉我你对她怎么看
Tell me what you think of her.
对谁怎么看？
Who?
玛格丽
Margaery.
她是一个理想的伴侣
She's an ideal match.
有提利尔家族相助
With the Tyrells beside us,
我们会打败北方人
we'll crush the Northerners.
杀死他们的领主 烧掉他们的要塞
Hang their lords, burn their strongholds,
给他们的庄稼撒盐
sow their fields with salt,
此后一个世纪都不会有人妄想造反了
and no one will think of rebelling for another century.
这没错 不过你对她本人的看法呢？
It is a good match, but what do you think of her?
她漂亮又聪明
She's beautiful and intelligent.
是的
Yes, she is.
她体恤平民百姓 很有意思
Her concern with the well-being of the common people is interesting.
我可不觉得有意思
Not to me.
我是说这种与你不同的做法 会危及――
I only meant that to go out of your way to endanger yourself--
这是我遇到过的
This is becoming one of the most boring
最无聊的对话之一了
conversations I've ever had.
玛格利・提利尔给肮脏的孤儿们捐献是有原因的
Margaery Tyrell dotes on filthy urchins for a reason.
她穿成荡妇的样子是有原因的
She dresses like a harlot for a reason.
她嫁给蓝礼・拜拉席恩这样的叛徒和众所周知的变态
She married a traitor and known degenerate
也是有原因的
like Renly Baratheon for a reason.
她嫁给蓝礼・拜拉席恩因为别人让她这么做
She married Renly Baratheon because she was told to.
这才是聪明的女人――
That's what intelligent women do--
照别人说的去做
what they're told.
- 你需要好好问问自己―― - 我不需要做任何事
- You need to ask yourself-- - I don't need to do anything.
好点了
Better.
好多了
Much better.
我仍然难以相信
I still don't believe it.
珊莎・史塔克
他一无所求
He didn't. He didn't want anything.
他帮我只是因为他爱着我母亲
He just takes an interest because he loved my mother.
男人从一个漂亮女孩那里只想得到一样东西
Men only want one thing from a pretty girl.
小指头不爱我
Littlefinger's not in love with me.
雪伊
珊莎的侍女 小恶魔的情人
爱情不是他想要的
Love is not the thing he wants.
他年纪太大了
He's too old.
男人们才不在乎
They never see it that way.
他没有让你为他做什么？
He didn't ask you to do something for him?
监视谁或者……？
Spy on someone or...?
没有
No.
不管他是要求你怎样
If he does ask you for anything
还是企图怎样
or try anything
抑或碰你 我要你告诉我
or touch you, I want you to tell me.
怎么？ 你会做什么？
Why? What will you do?
我会阻止他
I will make him stop.
洛拉斯・提利尔爵士 小姐
Ser Loras Tyrell, my lady.
让他进来
Send him in.
珊莎小姐
Lady Sansa.
洛拉斯爵士
Ser Loras.
我的妹妹玛格丽邀请你
My sister Margaery invites you to take
与她和我们祖母 奥莲娜夫人
the air with her and our grandmother
一起去花园里游玩
the Lady Olenna in the gardens.
要我护送您过去吗？
May I escort you to them?
您真是愈发的美丽了 珊莎小姐
I believe you grow more beautiful every day, Lady Sansa.
谢谢您 洛拉斯爵士
You are too kind, Ser Loras.
您也许不记得我们第一次见面了
You probably don't remember the first time we met.
洛拉斯・提利尔
“百花骑士”
在首相的比武大会上 您献花给我
At the Hand's tourney, you gave me your favor.
玫瑰 红色的玫瑰
A rose, a red rose.
哦我当然记得
Of course I did.
这才是属于你的颜色
It's more your color.
- 拿着 - 谢谢
- You take it. - Thank you.
你太可爱了
You're such a dear.
我要告退了
I'll take my leave.
珊莎小姐
Lady Sansa.
谢谢你 洛拉斯爵士
Thank you, Ser Loras.
来
Come.
珊莎小姐 我很荣幸
Lady Sansa, it is my honor
介绍我的祖母
to present my grandmother...
玛格丽・提利尔
乔佛里国王的未婚妻
提利尔家族的奥莲娜夫人
the Lady Olenna of House Tyrell.
奥莲娜夫人
亲我 孩子
Kiss me, child.
你真好心
It's so good of you to visit me
肯来和我及我这群蠢母鸡们共进晚餐
and my foolish flock of hens.
我们都为你逝去的亲人们感到遗憾
We're very sorry for your losses.
玛格丽小姐 当我听说蓝礼大人的死讯时 的确十分悲伤
And I was sorry when I heard of Lord Renly's death, Lady Margaery.
- 他是多么堂皇的人儿啊 - 没错 他堂皇
- He was very gallant. - Gallant, yes.
有魅力 澡也洗得干净
And charming and very clean.
他知道如何打扮 如何微笑
He knew how to dress and smile
从而得出结论自己该当国王
and somehow this gave him the notion he was fit to be king.
蓝礼既勇敢又温柔 祖母大人
Renly was brave and gentle, Grandmother.
父亲和洛拉斯都喜欢他
Father liked him and so did Loras.
洛拉斯还小
Loras is young and very good
善于用木棒把别人敲下马来
at knocking men off horses with a stick.
但这种运动不能让他变聪明
That does not make him wise.
至于你那痴呆的父亲――
As to your fathead father--
祖母大人！这会让珊莎怎么看我们？
Grandmother! What will Sansa think of us?
她会以为我们是一群风趣的人
She might think we have some wits about us.
不管怎么说 至少我们中有一员是这样
One of us, at any rate.
那是叛逆 我警告过他们
It was treason. I warned them.
劳勃有两个儿子 蓝礼还有位兄长
Robert has two sons and Renly has an older brother.
他怎么能要求
How could he possibly have any claim
那张丑陋的铁椅子呢
to that ugly iron chair?
如果你问我 我得说我们本应和这状该死的愚行保持距离
We should have stayed well out of all this if you ask me.
不过挤下的乳汁
But once the cow's been milked,
可不能注回乳房去
there's no squirting the cream back up her udders.
好了这就是我们看到的这事
So here we are to see things through.
你觉得怎么样 珊莎？
What do you say to that, Sansa?
来吃点柠檬蛋糕如何？
Shall we have some lemon cakes?
我最喜欢柠檬蛋糕了
Lemon cake's my favorite.
我们也是这么听说的
So we've been told.
你这是准备去拿食物呢还是想饿死我们？
Are you going to bring the food or do you mean to starve us to death?
来 珊莎
Here, Sansa,
和我坐一起
come sit with me.
我可比其他那些人有意思多了
I'm much less boring than these others.
认识我的儿子吗？
Do you know my son?
高庭公爵？
The Lord of Highgarden?
我还没有这个荣幸
I haven't had the pleasure.
这不是荣幸 相信我
No great pleasure, believe me.
他就是个大呆子
A ponderous oaf.
他爸同样是个呆子
His father was an oaf as well.
我指的是我丈夫 前任公爵罗斯
My husband, the late Lord Luthor.
猎鹰时 他竟从悬崖上掉了下去
He managed to ride off a cliff whilst hawking.
他们说 他一直盯着天空
They say he was looking up at the sky
根本没注意马
and paying no mind to where his horse was taking him.
而现在呢 我的白痴儿子也在干同样的蠢事
And now my son is doing the same,
只是他骑的换成了狮子而不是马
only this time he's riding a lion instead of a horse.
现在...
Now...
我希望你说实话
I want you to tell me the truth
关于这个小鬼国王 乔佛里
about this royal boy, this Joffrey.
我……我……
I... I...
你 你
You, you.
有谁比你更了解呢？
Who else would know better?
我们听说了许多令人困扰的谣言
We've heard some troubling tales.
这些谣言有没有真实的成分？
Is there any truth to them?
那小子虐待过你吗？
Has this boy mistreated you?
你的舌头教他拔了吗？
Has he ripped out your tongue?
小乔-- 乔佛里国王
Joff-- King Joffrey,
他-- 陛下他英俊又潇洒
he-- His Grace is very fair
而且像雄狮一样勇敢
and handsome and as brave as a lion.
是啊 兰尼斯特家的人都是狮子
Yes, all Lannisters are lions.
而提利尔放屁都有玫瑰的香味
And when a Tyrell farts, it smells like a rose.
他究竟怎么样？聪明吗？
But how kind is he? How clever?
有没有颗好心肠？能不能关心人？
Has he a good heart, a gentle hand?
我将要成为他的妻子
I'm to be his wife.
我想知道这意味着什么
I only want to know what that means.
给我些奶酪
Bring me some cheese.
蛋糕之后才上干酪 夫人
The cheese will be served after the cakes, my lady.
我想什么时候上就什么时候上
The cheese will be served when I want it served.
立刻把干酪给我端来
And I want it served now.
你在害怕 孩子？
Are you frightened, child?
别怕
No need for that.
在场的都是女人
We're only women here.
只管说实话 没人会伤害你
Tell us the truth. No harm will come to you.
我父亲总是说实话
My father always told the truth.
是的 他有那样的好名声
Yes, he had that reputation.
却被他们当作叛徒 砍了脑袋
And they named him traitor and took his head.
乔佛里
Joffrey.
是乔佛里干的
Joffrey did that.
他答应过我会手下留情 可依然砍了父亲的头
He promised he would be merciful and he cut my father's head off.
他说这就是手下留情
And he said that was mercy.
然后带我到城墙上 强迫我看
Then he took me up on the walls and made me look at it.
继续
Go on.
我-- 我不能说 我从没--
I-- I can't. I never meant--
我父亲是个叛徒
my father was a traitor.
我哥哥也是 我只是个叛徒之女
My brother as well. I have traitor's blood.
求求您们 别再让我说了
Please don't make me say anymore.
她吓坏了 祖母大人
She's terrified, Grandmother.
- 你看看她 - 放心说 孩子
- Just look at her. - Speak freely, child.
我们永远不会背叛你的信任 我发誓
We would never betray your confidence, I swear it.
他是个怪物
He's a monster.
啊
Ah.
这真遗憾
That's a pity.
求求您 千万别阻止婚礼
Please, don't stop the wedding.
别担心 高庭的呆子公爵
Have no fear. The Lord Oaf of Highgarden
下定决心要让玛格丽当上王后
is determined that Margaery shall be queen.
不管怎么说 我们感激你的实话
Even so, we thank you for the truth.
啊 奶酪来了
Ah, here comes my cheese.
灰风
罗柏・史塔克的冰原狼
我们还在打仗
We're at war.
这次行军毫无意义
This march is a distraction.
我外祖父的葬礼可不会没有意义
My grandfather's funeral is not a distraction.
- 我们这是要去奔流城打仗？ - 不是
- Are we riding to battle at Riverrun? - No.
看 就是毫无意义
Then it's a distraction.
我舅舅艾德慕有军队驻守那里
My Uncle Edmure has his forces garrisoned there.
瑞卡德・卡史塔克
卡霍城伯爵
我们需要他的人
We need his men.
除非他能变出更多来
Unless he's been breeding them,
否则这没太大的差别
he don't have enough to make a difference.
你对我们的目标失去信心了么？
Have you lost faith in our cause?
目标如果是复仇 我的信心就还在
If it's revenge, I still got faith in it.
如果你不再相信――
If you no longer believe--
我坚信 除非雪下到多恩
I can believe till it snows in Dorne.
但这改变不了我们以一敌二的处境
Don't change the fact that we've got half the men.
你不认为我们能赢？
You don't think we can win?
我可以直说吗 陛下？
May I speak my mind, Your Grace?
你一直没说实话吗 卡史塔克大人？
Have you not been speaking your mind, Lord Karstark?
我认为自从您和她结婚起
I think you lost this war
您就输了这场战争
the day you married her.
吁 吁
Whoa, whoa.
陛下
Your Grace.
你怕她
You're afraid of her.
- 她知道 - 我才不怕她
- And she knows it. - I'm not afraid of her.
可以效劳吗 史塔克夫人？
May I help you, Lady Stark?
不用
No.
我很抱歉 我不该--
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have--
你帮不上忙 因为一个母亲
You can't help because a mother
做这个是来保护她的孩子
makes one for her children to protect them.
只有母亲可以做这个
Only a mother can make them.
您以前做过这些？
You've made them before?
两次
Twice.
他们管用吗？
Did they work?
不怎么样
After a fashion.
我祈祷我的儿子布兰能在坠落重伤后挺过来
I prayed for my son Bran to survive his fall.
很多年前
Many years before that,
一个男孩子得疹子病倒了
one of the boys came down with the pox.
鲁温学士说如果他能挺过那个晚上 他就能活下去
Maester Luwin said if he made it through the night, he'd live.
但那是个很长的夜晚
But it would be a very long night.
于是我在黑暗中守在他身边
So I sat with him all through the darkness.
聆听他不规律的呼吸
Listened to his ragged little breaths,
他的咳嗽 他的呜咽
his coughing, his whimpering.
哪个男孩？
Which boy?
琼恩・雪诺
Jon Snow.
我丈夫把他从战争中带回家的时候
When my husband brought that baby home from the war,
我都没法直视他
I couldn't bear to look at him.
我不愿意看到他那双
I didn't want to see those brown
棕色的陌生的眼睛盯着我
stranger's eyes staring up at me.
于是我向七神祈祷 把他带走
So I prayed to the gods, take him away.
让他去死
Make him die.
他得了疹子
He got the pox.
于是我才发现我是世界上最糟糕的的女人
And I knew I was the worst woman who ever lived.
一个谋杀犯
A murderer.
我诅咒了这个可怜的 无辜的孩子
I'd condemned this poor, innocent child
咒他去死
to a horrible death
只是因为我嫉妒他的母亲
all because I was jealous of his mother.
一个他自己都不认识的女人
A woman he didn't even know.
因此我又向七神祈祷
So I prayed to all seven gods,
让这个男孩活下去
let the boy live.
让他活下去
Let him live
我会爱他
and I'll love him.
我会成为他的母亲
I'll be a mother to him.
我会请求丈夫给他正名
I'll beg my husband to give him a true name,
叫他史塔克
to call him Stark and be done with it,
让他成为我们的一员
to make him one of us.
他活下来了
And he lived.
活下来了
但是我没能守誓
And I couldn't keep my promise.
之后发生的这些...
And everything that's happened since then...
降临在我家族的灾难...
all this horror that's come to my family...
都是因为我没有去爱那个没有母亲的孩子
it's all because I couldn't love a motherless child.
琼恩・雪诺
叛逃的乌鸦
曼斯・雷德
“塞外之王”
杀死半掌科林很难吗？
Was it hard for you to kill the Halfhand?
是啊
Yes.
你喜欢他吗？
You liked him?
我喜欢你 但是如果你敢跟我们耍诈
I like you, but if you're playing us false,
杀了你可没这么难
it won't be hard for me to kill you.
我血管里流着野人的血
I've got wildling blood in my veins.
- 这些是我的人 - 我明白
- These are my people. - I understand.
嗯 你怎么会明白？
Well, how could you understand?
你想要保护你的人
You want to protect your people.
你知道把90个部族联合起来要多大的代价吗？
Do you know what it takes to unite 90 clans,
他们中的一半想要杀死另一半
half of whom want to massacre the other half
只是因为一两句口角
for one insult or another?
我的大军说七种不同的语言
They speak seven different languages in my army.
瑟恩人仇恨硬足民
The Thenns hate the Hornfoots.
硬足民仇恨冰川部落
The Hornfoots hate the ice-river clans.
所有人都仇恨穴居人
Everyone hates the cave people.
你知道我怎么让“拜月者”
So you know how I got moon worshippers
食人部族和巨人
and cannibals and giants
一起行军的吗？
to march together in the same army?
不知道
No.
我告诉他们如果我们到不了南方的话
I told them we were all going to die
我们都会死
if we don't get south.
因为这是事实
Because that's the truth.
不会太久
Shouldn't be long now.
他怎么了？
What's wrong with him?
他是个易形者
He's a warg.
他能进入动物 通过它们的眼睛观察
He can enter the mind of animals, see through their eyes.
他在为我们侦察
He's scouting for us.
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
什么 你从没遇到过易形者？
What, you've never met a warg?
欧瑞尔
Orell.
“鹰眼” 易形者
你这次跑哪去了？
Where were you this time?
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人掠袭者
先民拳锋
The Fist of the First Men.
你看到了什么？
What did you see?
死掉的乌鸦们
Dead crows.
你怎么了 猪崽?
What's the matter, Piggy?
你这是被冻哭了么?
You crying 'cause you're cold?
200名弟兄被死人杀掉
There's 200 brothers killed by dead men
山姆威尔・塔利
守夜人事务官
雷斯特
守夜人
而你竟然还在这里
and you're still here
哭哭啼啼的
whimpering.
对你来说可真公平！
That seem fair to you?
我看着他们坚持战斗直到被撕的支离破碎
I seen 'em torn to pieces fighting
鬼才知道那时你正藏在哪个山洞里
while you was off somewhere hiding in a hole.
你为什么不躺下来休息一会呢 嗯？
Why don't you lie down and rest for a while, eh?
你知道你想这样的
You know you want to.
葛兰
守夜人游骑兵
嘿
Hey.
快起来 山姆
Get up, Sam.
- 不 - 站起来
- No. - Get up.
我做不到
I can't.
如果你停下来 你就会死的
If you stop, you'll die.
当然就算你不停下来 你也未必能活下来
'Course if you don't stop, you'll probably die, too.
艾迪森・托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
- 你们才不在乎我  - 我们当然在乎
- You don't care. - 'Course we care.
你们抛弃了我
You left me.
当异鬼出现的时候 你们抛弃了我
When the white walkers came, you left me.
是啊 我们抛弃了你
Aye, we left you.
你又肥又慢腾腾的
You're fat and you're slow.
我们可不想死
We didn't want to die.
帮我把他抬起来
Help me get him up.
看起来猪崽要完蛋了
Looks like that piggy is done for.
- 帮我们把他抬起来 - 他在拖我们的后腿
- Help us get him up. - He's slowing us down.
把他抬起来！
Just get him up!
为什么？为了让他害死我们所有人？
Why? So the rest of us can die?
没有他我们走的更快
We'll move faster without him.
这是怎么回事？塔利 站起来
What is this? Get up, Tarly.
杰奥・莫尔蒙
“熊老” 守夜人总司令
- 他还好么 - 是的 我觉得他还好
- Is he all right? - Aye, I think so.
如果他做不到 我们也得丢下他接着行进
If he can't, we may as well just go without him.
够了
That's enough.
塔利
Tarly,
我不许你死
I forbid you to die.
你听见了么
Do you hear me?
- 凭什么我们-- - 雷斯特...
- Why should the rest of us-- - Rast...
他现在归你负责了
you're responsible for him.
我要做什么？
What am I supposed to do?
确保他活着回来
Make sure he gets back alive.
如果他死了 你也别回来
If he doesn't, you don't.
继续前进！
Move on!
我不会为你而死的 猪崽
I'm not dying for you, Piggy.
你听见我的话了吗？
You hear me?
瑞肯和阿多去哪了？
Where's Rickon and Hodor?
去找吃的去了
Looking for food.
那是什么？
What's out there?
站在这别动 小子
Not another step, boy.
除非你想被自己的血淹死
Unless you want to drown in your own blood.
我没带武器
I'm unarmed.
你的计划烂透了
That was poor planning.
我的姐姐带武器了
My sister carries the weapons.
我更擅长使用它们
I'm better with them.
把矛放下
Drop the spear.
放下
Drop it.
就算你杀了我
If you kill me,
那头狼也会把你撕成碎片
that wolf will tear you to bits.
你一定就是夏天了
You must be Summer.
我叫玖健・黎德
I'm Jojen Reed.
这是我的姐姐梅拉
This is my sister Meera.
梅拉・黎德
玖健・黎德
我们为了见到你走了好长的路 布兰登
We've come a long way to find you, Brandon.
而我们的前路会更加漫长
And we have much farther to go.
我只是想搞明白
I'm just trying to understand.
拜托你闭嘴别提这件事了好吗？
Would you please shut up about it?
贾坤・赫加尔帮你杀了三次人
Jaqen H'ghar offered you three kills.
- 我不听 - 给我解释一下好吗
- I'm not listening. - But just explain it to me.
他可以帮你随便杀三个人
He offered to kill any three people you wanted.
你只需要给他要杀的人的名字
Dead. All you had to do was give him the names.
任何人 你可以选乔佛里国王
Anyone. You could have picked King Joffrey.
- 闭嘴 - 你可以选泰温・兰尼斯特
- Shut up. - You could have picked Tywin Lannister.
贾坤帮我们离开了赫伦堡
Jaqen got us out of Harrenhal,
你还有什么可抱怨的？
so why are you complaining?
但你本可以结束这场战争
But you could have ended the war.
- 我们要往哪去？ - 北方
- Where are we going? - North.
如果我们是朝北走的
If we were going north,
现在应该已经到红叉河了
we should have come to the Red Fork River by now.
或许我们已经过了那条河了
Maybe we already passed it.
艾莉亚・史塔克
那条河有一百尺宽呢
It's 100 feet wide.
我们怎么可能已经过去了
How could we have passed it?
詹德利
“大牛” 铁匠学徒
“热派”
如果我们到了红叉河
If we hit the Red Fork,
我们就可以沿着它向西走到奔流城
we can follow it west to Riverrun.
我妈妈在那里长大
My mother grew up there.
我的外祖父是那的公爵 他会保护我们的
My grandfather's a lord. He'll protect us.
大概是个歌手
Could be a minstrel.
闭嘴
Shut up.
爪牙锋利不留情
A lion still has claws...
歌手身上可能会带钱
A minstrel's got gold sometimes.
我们可以偷袭他 把他捆起来 抢走他的金子
We could jump him, tie him up, steal his gold,
- 再去买点吃的 - 嘘
- and buy some food. - Shh.
噢 他这样说 他这样说
And so he spoke, and so he spoke
卡斯特梅的爵爷他这样说
That Lord of Castamere
然而今天 每逢雨季
But now the rains
雨水在大厅哭泣 内里却无人影
Weep o'er his hall
内里却无人影
With no one there to hear.
那堵墙后面藏的是什么东西？
What's lurking behind that wall?
狮子？还是狼？
A lion? A wolf?
要我说就是头脏兮兮的小崽子
Just a dirty little cub, I think.
- 射几箭过去 - 不要
- Loose a few more shafts. - Don't.
快把剑放下 小姑娘
Put the sword down, girl.
你们沿着小路继续往前走
You go on down the road.
你继续唱歌 好让我知道你已经走了
Just keep on singing so we know where you are.
走开 别来惹我们 我就不杀你
Leave us be and I won't kill you.
真是宽宏大量
Generous.
你是个危险的人
You're a dangerous person.
我喜欢危险的人
I like dangerous people.
为什么你的朋友们那么害羞？
Why are your friends so shy?
什么朋友？
What friends?
你左边的胖子和他身边的小子
The fat one to your left and the lad beside him.
三个小孩子在奔逃
Three young ones on the run
带着城堡里打造的剑
carrying castle-forged swords.
你们是从赫伦堡逃出来的吗？
You escape from Harrenhal?
- 你们是谁？ - 密尔的索罗斯
- Who are you? - Thoros of Myr.
这边带弓的伙计叫安盖
And the fellow here with the bow is Anguy.
密尔的索罗斯
无旗兄弟会的红袍僧
安盖
“射手” 来自风暴地的弓箭手
不 我问的是你们为谁而战？
No, who do you fight for?
无旗兄弟会
The Brotherhood without Banners.
现在 跟我们来
Now come along.
我想知道两个小子
I want to hear how two boys
和一个非常危险的女孩是怎么逃离赫伦堡的
and a very dangerous girl escaped Harrenhal.
我不想跟他们走 这个兄弟会
I'm not going with them. The Brotherhood?
就是魔山和他的属下正在追寻的
That's who the Mountain and them lot were looking for.
魔山会把我们一起抓回去喂老鼠的
They'll bring us back and put rats in us.
你不需要害怕我们 小子
You've got nothing to fear from us, son.
维斯特洛的领主老爷们想要战火烧遍我们的土地
The lords of Westeros want to burn the countryside.
我们正努力拯救它
We're trying to save it.
快来
Now come on.
咱们还是化干戈为玉帛 吃些棕面包和煮菜吧
We'll talk some more over brown bread and stew.
然后你们就可以接着赶你们的路了
And then you can go on your way.
我跟你说 你这胖子
Here's the thing, fat boy.
当我的话结束的时候
When I'm done talking,
这枝箭就会落到你的脑袋上
that arrow's falling down on your fat head.
所以呢 我建议你赶紧挪个地方 因为我的话已经说完了
So I advise you move, because I'm done talking.
半个国度都在挨饿 而看看这家伙
Half the country's starving and look at this one.
或许他就是半个国度都在挨饿的缘故罢
Maybe he's the reason half the country's starving.
我的狮子
My lion.
我们说过这事
We've spoken of this.
你不可以来这儿
You cannot come here.
提利昂・兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
但你说过如果我有麻烦就应该来找你
But you said I should come to you with any problems.
有人看见你来这吗？
Did anyone see you?
- 没有 - 你确定？
- No. - You sure?
我的父亲绝不会虚张声势
My father does not make idle threats.
杀掉你会让他这周过的很愉快的
Having you killed would be the high point of his week.
你必须保证绝对没人看到你来
You have to be absolutely certain.
好吧
All right.
你的麻烦到底是什么？
What is this problem?
我在担心珊莎
I'm worried about Sansa.
她和贝里席大人讲话的时候
When she spoke with Lord Baelish,
他的一位朋友跟我警告他
his friend warned me about him.
贝里席没有朋友
Baelish doesn't have friends.
我不知道她的名字
I don't know her name.
- 哦 萝丝吗？红头发的那个？ - 你怎么知道她的？
- Oh, Ros? The redhead? - How do you know her?
我努力认识尽可能多的人
I try to know as many people as I can.
说不定什么时候你就会需要他们
You never know which one you'll need.
她是个妓女
She's a whore.
是的 好吧 我们不要动辄就对这种事评头论足
Yes, well, we shouldn't be judgmental about these things.
- 你上过她 - 噢 别这样
- You fucked her. - Oh, please.
好吧 我确实上过她一次
All right, yes, I fucked her once.
两次
Twice.
但自从遇见你之后 我的女士
But since I met you, my lady,
我再没有跟其他任何人在一起过
I've been with no one else.
她活儿好么？你喜欢她吗？
And was she good? Did you like her?
很明显我更喜欢你
Not as much as I like you, obviously,
否则现在就会是她在折磨我了
or she'd be the one torturing me right now.
关于小指头 她和你说了些什么？
What did she say about Littlefinger?
她说珊莎不应该相信他
That Sansa shouldn't trust him.
难道这世界上
Is there an idiot in any village
还会有相信小指头的白痴？
who trusts Littlefinger?
我们应该去保护她
We have to protect her.
我们做不到
We can't.
现在兰尼斯特放弃了她
Now that the Lannisters have discarded her,
珊莎会有很多追求者
Sansa will have many suitors.
她是个大美人 有着古老的姓氏
A great beauty with a very old name.
大美人？噢 她是个大美人？
A great beauty? Oh, a great beauty?
是的 她当然是 非常美
Yes, she is, objectively, very.
她的脸蛋多么可人--
Her face is quite pleasing--
别的男人 还有女人
to other men and to women,
普通人都这么觉得
people in general.
当然 不包括我在内
But not to me, of course.
我的眼中只有你
I only have eyes for you.
你这变态 你想要她？
You pervert. You want her?
- 这个孩子？ - 我都没想要提起她
- This child? - I don't even want to talk about her.
- 但你提了 - 那是你逼我说的
- But you are. - Only because you're making me.
我可没逼你张口
I didn't force you to open your mouth
逼你说出这些话
and make words come out.
你可真是残忍而不公 残忍而不公平
This is cruel and unfair. Cruelly unfair.
"哦 残忍
"Oh, the cruelty.
雪伊对我好残忍"
Shae is so cruel to me."
是啊
Hmm, yes.
现在你还觉得我残忍吗？
Now do you think I'm cruel?
如果你就这样停下
Only if you stop.
但你不可以再到我这里了
But you mustn't come here again.
你听见我的话了吗？
Do you hear me?
你身处一个危险的地方
You've come to a dangerous place
充斥着危险的人
full of dangerous people.
危险的人呐
Dangerous people.
国王陛下 提利尔小姐求见
Lady Tyrell, my king.
让她进来
Send her in.
陛下 您想见我？
You wanted to see me, Your Grace?
我要外出打猎
I'm leaving on a hunting trip.
我只是想确保
I just wanted to make sure
在我离开前你一切安好
you had everything you need before I left.
您可真是体贴啊 陛下
That's very thoughtful, Your Grace.
在这里我有我想要的一切
I have everything I could want.
很好 很好
Good. Good.
你在都城的日子过的如何
How are you finding life in the capital?
跟在蓝礼的军营相比一定有很大的变化
It must be quite a change after Renly's camp.
好的变化
A welcome one.
军营不是淑女应该呆的地方
A military encampment is no place for a lady.
那叛徒的枕边呢？
And the bedside of a traitor?
难道那是淑女该在的地方吗？
Is that a place for a lady?
陛下
Your Grace,
我只是试图尽我做妻子的责任而已
I tried to do my duty as a wife, that is all.
那你觉得你对这个叛徒有什么样的责任
What was your duty to this traitor as you saw it?
任何妻子对丈夫的责任--
The duty of any wife to any husband--
给他生孩子
to provide him with children.
你没做到这点
You failed to do this.
- 为什么？ - 我--
- Why? - I--
我不想说逝者的坏话 陛下
I would not speak ill of the dead, Your Grace.
你觉得你应该讲叛徒的好话
You think one ought to speak kindly
仅仅因为他被人一剑穿心？
of a traitor merely because he's had a sword put through his heart?
不
No.
我恳请您的原谅
I do beg your pardon.
我总把握不到政治的精微之处
The subtleties of politics are often lost on me.
蓝礼...
Renly...
我认为他
I don't believe he was interested
对女人的陪伴没有兴趣
in the company of women.
你为什么这么说？
What makes you say this?
每当我想为他生个孩子
Whenever I wanted to make a child with him,
他――
he--
他总是找理由敷衍
he had so many excuses,
总说有什么深夜作战会议
so many late-night war councils.
他连试一试都不愿意
He never wanted to try.
只是有一天晚上
Except one evening,
那晚他酒喝得实在有点多了
after he'd had far too much wine to drink,
他提出某种――
he suggested something--
某种听上去就疼死人
something that sounded very painful
而且根本不会使我怀孕的动作
and couldn't possibly result in children.
也许这是我的错
Maybe the fault was with me.
不 谁都知道他是个……
No, he was a known...
精神病
degenerate.
您能这么说我就放心了 陛下
It's such a relief to hear you say so, Your Grace.
嗯
Mmm.
我曾考虑过以性变态的名义
I've considered making his perversion
将他处死
punishable by death.
您有权这么做
As is your right.
您该做什么就一定要去做
You must do whatever you need to do.
您是国王
You are the king.
当然
Yes.
这还用说
I am.
您喜欢这个？
Do you like it?
我刚刚让人打造了它
I just had it made.
这也许是七国上下最出色的武器之一
Probably one of the finest weapons in the Seven Kingdoms.
它可真漂亮
It's beautiful.
您能向我展示一下它怎么工作吗？
Will you show me how it works?
这是款新的设计
It's a new design.
装填起来更加容易 没什么曲柄
Much easier to load. There's no crank.
你用这个东西给弓上弦
You use this lever to draw the string.
再把箭放在这儿
The bolt goes here.
然后你只需要瞄准……
And then you just aim...
然后……
and...
你能找时间带我去打猎吗？
Would you take me hunting sometime?
请原谅我 陛下
Forgive me, Your Grace.
我知道打猎不是女人家的游戏
I know a hunt is no place for a woman.
老生常谈
It's not unheard of.
我父亲以前从没让我――
My father would never let me before--
你再也不属于他了
You no longer belong to him.
你想试试吗？
Do you want to hold it?
我可以吗？给我吧
May I? Please.
我觉得只要在胸前动动手指
I imagine it must be so exciting
就能将那么远处的什么东西
to squeeze your finger here
给射杀 一定非常刺激
and watch something die over there.
你能做到吗？
Could you do it?
你敢……
Could you...
杀生吗？
kill something?
我不知道 陛下 您觉得我能不能呢？
I don't know, Your Grace. Do you think I could?
能啊
Yes.
您愿意看着我吗？
Would you like to watch me?
当然
Yes.
停下！快停下！
Stop! Stop!
- 告诉我们真相 - 什么真相？
- Tell us the truth. - About what?
我不知道你想了解什么啊
I don't know what you want.
我想了解真相
I want the truth.
什么真相？
What truth?
你为何攻占临冬城？
Why'd you take Winterfell?
我攻占它为了―― 我攻占它――
I took it to-- I took it--
- 谁下的命令？ - 谁也没下
- Who gave the orders? - No one.
- 是我一个人干的 -为什么？
- I took it on my own. - Why?
为了趁守备空虚的时候夺取北境
To take the North while it was vulnerable.
你占领临冬城后准备做什么？
What were you going to do once you took it?
守住它 统治它
Hold it. Rule it.
很好 非常好
Good. That's very good.
你这是为什么？我都告诉你了
Why did you do that? I told you.
你为何攻占临冬城？
Why did you take Winterfell?
为了给我的家族和我父亲带去荣耀
I took it to bring glory to my house and my father.
等等 等一下 等一下
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
我攻占它是因为我恨史塔克
I took it because I hated the Starks.
恨他们将我作为犯人囚禁
I hated them for holding me prisoner.
我想报复他们
I wanted to hurt them.
你要干嘛？
What are you doing?
求你了
Please.
我可以告诉你一切
I'll tell you anything.
头套摘下来也好啊
Just take it off.
求你了 求你把头套摘下来吧
Please. Please, just take it off.
- 你姐姐派我来的 - 雅拉？
- Your sister sent me. - Yara?
今晚整座城入睡后我来找你
I'll come for you tonight when the castle sleeps.
不 别走 求你了 求你别走
No, don't go. Please, please.
不 求你别丢下我
No, please don't leave me.
求你了 求你了
Please, please.
求你了 求你别走啊！
Please, please don't go!
求你了 求你别走 别丢下我
Please. Please. Don't leave me.
求求你不要走啊
Please don't go.
瑞肯 跟我们一起走
Rickon, stay with us.
没关系 冰原狼会护着他的
It's all right. The wolves will protect him.
你能进入他的思想
You can get inside his head,
通过它的双眼来观察
see through his eyes.
只有睡着的时候才行
Only when I'm asleep.
在你学会如何控制它之前确实是这样的
That's how it begins until you learn to control it.
你是个狼灵
You're a warg.
不只是狼
It's not just wolves.
有时候在我的梦里 有一只――
Sometimes in my dreams there's a--
- 一只三眼乌鸦？ -你见过它？
- A three-eyed raven? - You've seen it?
我们一起看到的 你应该还没忘记吧？
We saw him together. You haven't forgotten?
这和我是狼灵有什么联系吗？
Does it have anything to do with warging?
不 乌鸦是另一种不同的东西
No, the raven is something different,
一种更深层次的
something deeper.
乌鸦能够开启你的双眼
The raven brings the sight.
看见那些还没发生的事？
Seeing things that haven't happened yet?
或者是那些远在你出生之前就发生过的
Or things that happened long before you were born
或是正在发生但却距你千里之遥的事情
or things that are happening right now thousands of miles away.
他跟他说什么呢？
What's he telling him?
你问这干嘛？
Why don't you ask?
你弟弟难道不害臊吗
Isn't he ashamed, your brother,
长这么大还需要你来保护
needing you to protect him?
这有什么可害臊的？
Where's the shame in that?
一个男孩这么大还需要姐姐保护
Any boy his age who needs his sister to protect him
他自己做不到的事情就会越来越多
is gonna find himself needing lots of protecting.
有些人总是需要别人的帮助
Some people will always need help.
但这并不意味着不值得去帮助他们
That doesn't mean they're not worth helping.
我父亲去世时 我梦到了
When my father died, I dreamt it.
你不是梦到了 而是预见到了
You didn't dream it. You saw it.
我也一样
So did I.
你也有那种感知能力？
You have the sight, too?
当我跟我父亲说起你的父亲……
When I told my father about your father...
他哭了 我以前从没见过他哭
for the first time in my life, I saw him cry.
你父亲是霍兰・黎德？
Your father is Howland Reed?
是啊
Yeah.
他在反叛期间救过我父亲的命
He saved my father's life during the rebellion.
你父亲跟你说过反叛的事？
Your father told you about the rebellion?
我父亲从来不提
Mine never did.
但我还是能看到
But I saw that, too.
你还看到过什么？
What else have you seen?
只有一件要紧的事情――
Only one thing that matters--
你
you.
我从来都不喜欢又瘦又小的杯子
I never liked the skinny ones.
就像从洞里喝水
Like drinking from a puddle.
不是说我讨厌喝“洞”里的水
Not that I'm averse to drinking from a puddle
从来都不是 你懂的
every now and again, you understand.
我不喝麦芽酒
I don't drink ale.
再好听的故事 喝点儿酒听起来也会更有趣
There's no story so good a drink won't make it better.
- 是啊！ -看见了？
- Yeah! - You see?
我节酒那阵子他们都受够了
They've all suffered through my bouts of sobriety.
对任何人来说那都无聊透顶
It's very tedious for all concerned.
来说说吧 你们三个小孩子是怎么――
Now, how did three children--
我们不是小孩子
We're not children.
像你们三个这样的年轻人
How did three young persons such as yourselves,
从未受过军事训练
untrained in the art of war,
是怎么逃出赫伦堡的？
escape from Harrenhal?
詹德利是个铁匠
Gendry's a smith.
他在铁匠铺里当过学徒
He was apprenticed in the armory.
当过学徒 嗯？哪个铺子？
A smith, eh? Where'd you train?
君临 托布・莫特的铺子
King's Landing. Tobho Mott's shop.
那个死家伙 他要价
That criminal. He charges twice as much
是城里其他铁匠的两倍
as every other armorer in the city.
那是因为他比别的铁匠优秀两倍
That's because he's twice as good.
啊哈！又当学徒又搞推销
Aha! A smith and a salesman.
詹德利把武器偷出来给我们
Gendry stole us weapons.
啊 从赫伦堡里杀出来一条路啊 我懂了
Ah, fought your way out of Harrenhal, I see.
他知道如何使剑 我也一样
He knows how to use a sword and so do I.
我哥哥教我的
My brothers taught me.
噢！
Ooh!
为你哥哥干杯！
To your brothers!
你们可以吃完再动身
You can finish your meals before you go.
路上想见到下一家不知要到什么时候
It may be awhile before you see another.
- 你会放我们走？ - 我向你保证
- You'll free us? - I gave you my word.
但是在你们动身之前
But before you go,
请允许我举杯为你的――
allow me to raise a cup to your--
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
话说 这可真是少见的大块头啊
Now that is an uncommonly large person.
你们是怎么制服
How does one manage to subdue
这么个大个子的？
such an uncommonly large person?
当然是等他喝的烂醉如泥再动手啦
One waits for him to drink until he passes out.
可怜人啊 我都开始同情你了
Poor man. You have my sympathy.
啊哈 这哪是个人啊
Aha, not a man at all.
是只猎狗！
A Hound!
再次见到你可真好 克里冈
So good to see you again, Clegane.
索罗斯
Thoros?
你他妈在这儿干嘛？
The fuck you doing here?
喝酒侃大山啊
Drinking and talking too much.
和以前一样
Same as ever.
- 价钱很公道啊 伙计们 - 是啊！
- A pretty prize, lads. - Yeah!
丫头
Girl.
桑铎・克里冈
“猎狗”
七层地狱的
What in seven hells
你跟这只史塔克小母狼在干嘛？
are you doing with the Stark bitch?
这真是个艰难的决定――
It's a tough decision--
冒着被人发现的风险过桥呢
take the bridge and risk being seen
还是游过宽广的河面
or cross the great water.
- 闭嘴 弑君者 - 在桥上任何人都看得到我们
- Silence, Kingslayer. - Anyone can see us on the bridge,
但是从水里游过去 水流可能会把我们卷走
but cross by water and the current could take us
或者 我会趁机顺着水流逃走
or I could escape down the river.
祝你好运
Good luck.
看你进退两难真是妙极了
It's wonderful to watch you wrestle with these dilemmas.
她会选哪种呢
Which will she choose?
你骨子里就是个赌徒
Gambler at heart.
猜都不用猜
Wouldn't have guessed.
你走快点
Be quick about it.
- 我需要歇一会儿 - 站起来
- I need to rest. - Get up.
我长了 你知道 走得久了就会长在你脚上的那个东西
I have these, you know, on your feet when you walk too far.
- 那些玩意儿叫什么？ - 立刻站起来
- What do you call them? - Get up now.
鸡眼 我从来没长过鸡眼
Corns. I never used to get corns.
当然啦 我去哪儿都是骑着马的
Of course I used to ride everywhere,
不会像个普通的步兵那样
not march around like a common foot soldier
一整年都穿着一双烂靴子走来走去
wearing the same shit boots for over a year.
脚后跟都烂掉了 根本没法――
This heel is ruined. There's no way--
我怎么也想不通为什么有些骑士觉得自己需要两把剑
I never understood why some knights felt the need to carry two swords.
喔
Ooh.
你步法不错
You move well...
对于一个大个儿妞儿而言
for a great beast of a woman.
你不该在突刺之前把脸绷成那个样
You shouldn't grimace before you lunge.
游戏不是这么玩的
It gives away the game.
对你来说有点不太好办吧
Bit of a quandary for you.
你要是杀了我 就辜负了史塔克夫人
If you kill me, you fail Lady Stark.
但你要是不杀我
But if you don't kill me,
那我就会杀了你
I'm going to kill you.
你挺在行啊
You're good.
不好看 但很厉害
Graceless, but good.
看吧 你要是想伤害我的话
See? If you were willing to hurt me,
刚才在那儿你也许就得手了
you might have had me there.
看上去你女人比你厉害啊
Looks like your woman's getting the better of you,
如果你能管那货叫女人
if you can call that a woman.
我们正打得尽兴呢
We enjoy a good fight.
好好舒活一下筋骨
Gets our juices flowing.
波顿家的剥皮人
The Flayed Man of House Bolton.
就我看来有点毛骨悚然
A bit gruesome for my taste.
- 你确定他就是那个人？ - 就是他 没错
- You sure he's the one? - That's him, all right.
我在威廉・佛雷爵士婚礼的
I saw him fight at the tourney
比武会上见他战斗过
for Ser Willem Frey's wedding.
把银子给他吧
Give the man his silver.
放我们走 你想要什么我老爸都会给
Let us go and my father will pay you whatever you want.
足够我买个新脑袋吗？
Enough to buy me a new head?
要是北境之王听说我抓住了弑君者
If the King in the North hears I had the Kingslayer
却又放他走了 他当时就会要了我这颗脑袋
and let him go, he'll be taking it right off.
我倒更希望他要你的脑袋
I'd rather he takes yours.
衣柜字幕组出品